<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CroFert</string>
    <string name="about_fertiliser">Fertilizer consumption in India has increased signifi-cantly in the last three decades. Total NPK (N, P2O5 and K2O) consumption increased nine-fold (from 2 million to 18 million tonnes) between 1969/1970 and 1999/2000. Per-hectare NPK consumption increased from 11 to 95 kg in the same period. After reaching a record level in 1999/2000, fertilizer consumption in India has been irregular. It has fluctuated around 17 million tonnes since 2000/01.
    Fertilizer consumption varies widely between the AEZ owing to the substantial differences in soil type, fertility status, crop, weather, rainfall, irrigation facilities, etc. (Table 12). AEZ 4 was the most important region in terms of fertilizer use and consumed 3.5 million tonnes of fertilizer (21 percent of the total) in 2003/04 on 30 million ha of cropped area. In six AEZs (Nos. 2, 4, 6, 7, 9 and 13), the annual fertilizer consumption has exceeded one million tonnes and together they accounted for about 63 percent of total fertilizer consumption.</string>

    <string name="fertilizer_imp">Just as humans need essential minerals and nutrients for strong, healthy growth, so do the world\'s crops. Our core business of fertilizer production is intimately connected with agricultural productivity and food production. The role of fertilizers in food production is usually underestimated. Fertilizers are food for plants.Fertilizers replace the nutrients that crops remove from the soil. Without the addition of fertilizers, crop yields and agricultural productivity would be significantly reduced. That’s why mineral fertilizers are used to supplement the soil’s nutrient stocks with minerals that can be quickly absorbed and used by crops.Thus, in order to meet human nutritional needs in the crops and meat we eat, we need to replace what we take out. The key is to get this balance right and to maintain a level of nutrients in soils that will support our crops without applying excess.</string>

    <string-array name="crop_array">
        <item>Select Option</item>
        <item>Rice</item>
        <item>Wheat</item>
        <item>Maize</item>
        <item>Millet</item>
        <item>Pulse</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="about_farmers">The Indian farmer is a living idol of India, as they are the most hardworking farmers around the world and always busy, working hard for their crops, during day and night.

India is called the land of farmers, as most of the people of the country are directly or indirectly involved in the agriculture sector.It would not be wrong to say that ‘Indian farmers’ are the backbone of the economy and the farmers are indeed the beloved children of Mother India.Farming is the process of growing a wide variety of crops; India has a diverse culture, with approximately 22 major languages and 720 homeland languages spoken in India. People from all the religions like Hindu, Christian, Islam and Sikh live in India and they are engaged in various occupations, but agriculture is the main occupation.

“Indian Farmer” has the ability to survive with the various seasons, climate change, soil conditions and often harsh destruction of wildfires, droughts and floods.</string>

    <string name="wheat_desc">Wheat is a grass widely cultivated for its seed, a cereal grain which is a worldwide staple food.he many species of wheat together make up the genus Triticum; the most widely grown is common wheat (T. aestivum). The archaeological record suggests that wheat was first cultivated in the regions of the Fertile Crescent around 9600 BCE. Botanically, the wheat kernel is a type of fruit called a caryopsis.Wheat is grown on more land area than any other food crop (220.4 million hectares, 2014).
    World trade in wheat is greater than for all other crops combined. In 2017, world production of wheat was 772 million tonnes, with a forecast of 2019 production at 766 million tonnes, making it the second most-produced cereal after maize.Since 1960, world production of wheat and other grain crops has tripled and is expected to grow further through the middle of the 21st century. Global demand for wheat is increasing due to the unique viscoelastic and adhesive properties of gluten proteins, which facilitate the production of processed foods, whose consumption is increasing as a result of the worldwide industrialization process and the westernization of the diet.</string>

    <string name="maize_desc">Maize (Zea mays L.) is the world’s leading crop and is widely cultivated as cereal grain that was domesticated in Central America. It is one of the most versatile emerging crops having wider adaptability. Globally, maize is known as queen of cereals because of its highest genetic yield potential. Maize is the only food cereal crop that can be grown in diverse seasons, ecologies and uses. Beside this maize have many types like normal yellow/ white grain, sweet corn, baby corn, popcorn, waxy corn, high amylase corn, high oil corn, quality protein maize, etc. Apart from this, maize is an important industrial raw material and provides large opportunity for value addition.Maize belongs to the tribe Maydeae of the grass family Poaceae. “Zea” was derived from an old Greek name for a food grass. The genus Zea consists of four species of which Zea mays L. is economically important. The other Zea sp., referred to as teosinte, is largely wild grass native to Mexico and Central America. The number of chromosomes in Zea mays is 2 n = 20. Tribe Maydeae comprises seven genera which are recognized, namely Old and New World groups. Old World comprises Coix (2n = 10/20), Chionachne (2n = 20), Sclerachne (2n = 20), Trilobachne (2n = 20) and Polytoca (2n = 20), and New World group has Zea and Tripsacum. It is generally agreed that maize phylogeny was largely determined by the American genera Zea and Tripsacum, however it is accepted that the genus Coix contributed to the phylogenetic development of the species Zea mays.</string>

    <string name="rice_desc">There are only two species of cultivated rice in the world, Oryza sativa (Asian rice) and Oryza glaberrima (African rice). Both species are annual grasses (except in the tropics, where the plant can be perennial) belonging to the family Poaceae which are cultivated for their grain which is considered a staple food in most parts of the world. Asian and African rice plants are morphologically very similar and can be difficult to tell apart. They have rounded stems (called culms) which are divided into nodes and internodes. The plant leaves are borne on the nodes of the stem and are long and slender with a pronounced midrib. The plant produces three flowers, two of which are reduced, on a spikelet on the terminal (last) internode of the stem. The rice grain is formed by the ripened ovary of the flower and is between 5 and 12 mm in length. Rice is an annual plant, harvested after one growing season and can reach a height of between 1 and 1.8 m (3.3–5.9 ft) depending on variety. Generally, African rice tends to form smaller, pear shaped grains with a red bran and olive to black seed coat and has several disadvantages compared with its Asian counterpart e.g. seed is easily scattered, the grain is difficult to mill and the crop gives a lower yield. The growing of Asian rice has therefore begun to supercede that of African rice in West Africa. Asian rice originates from China and African rice is believed to have been domesticated in areas around the Niger river in Africa.</string>

</resources>